Just to recap and summarize our grip.
Remember you are going to grip the racket and you turn it like that so the racket faces open.
Grip the racket and turn it like that and that is what it should look like.
If you have a nice grip it allows you to come underneath the ball and open the face, under spin is the key to good squash.
It is not like tennis where we hit top spin.
In this game if you hit top spin you are going to drive it in to the tin and you are going to lose a lot of points.
To be able to get the ball deep into the court you are going to have to have the racket open so you can hit the ball with some loft so the grip is really the foundation of everything.
If you have a good grip that is going to force you to move in certain ways.
See if I have a bad grip where I can use arm and shoulder I can move the ball any way I want because I will just adjust with my hand and arm but I will hit a bad shot virtually every time.
The same goes on the forehand.
If I have a bad grip I can hit all types of bad shots but if I have the proper grip I am going to be much more cognizant of staying away from the ball and hitting a good shot.
So the idea of why the grip is such a simple concept but it is so overlooked because people are always looking for those big improvements but the fastest way to improve your game is to get a good grip so that once again it is that open face on both sides so you see how you open the face and if you do that you will be able to hit a nice loft on the ball and you will have a good shot so remember with an open face that is an easy shot.
With a closed face it is no good so open the face and your game will be good.